Makise... Kurisu?!
（岡部倫太郎(おかべりんたろう)）牧瀬(まきせ)… 紅莉栖(くりす)
I did knock, for what it's worth.
（牧瀬紅莉栖）
一応 ノックはしたんですけど
How did you find this place?
（岡部）な…
なぜ ここを？
I asked Mr. Hashida.
（紅莉栖）
橋田(はしだ)さんに聞いて来たんです
He called it a "laboratory,"
“ラボラトリー”っていうから―
so I was expecting something grander than this...
もう少し
ちゃんとした所かと思ったん…
Daru, did you betray me?
（岡部）ダル！
まさか 裏切ったのか？
（橋田 至(いたる)）はあ？
You were deceived by this three-dimensional woman's wiles...
この３次元女の色香に
惑わされて
I'll never forgive you! Ever!
貴様 許さん　許さんぞお！
You...
このビーッチが！
Bitch!
Can you do anything about him?
（紅莉栖）
何とかしてもらえませんか？
Just consider him confused by certain current events.
この状況に
混乱していると思われ
This is an emergency.
（岡部）緊急事態だ
The Organization has finally sent an agent of theirs to the lab!
機関が ついにここまで
エージェントを送り込んできた
なに？
What?
Then is this, too, the choice of Steins Gate?
これもシュタインズ･ゲートの
選択だというのか？
Steins Gate?
“シュタインズ･ゲート”？
Something Okarin made up.
オカリンの脳内設定
特に意味はない
It doesn't really mean anything.
Seems so.
…でしょうね
ドイツ語と英語が混在してるし
He's mixing up his German and English.
Take your shoes off!
（岡部）靴を脱げ
へ？ ああ 失礼
I'm sorry.
I've been in America for too long.
ずっとアメリカだったもので
なっ…
（紅莉栖）
改めまして 牧瀬紅莉栖です
Nice to meet you.
I'm Makise Kurisu.
あ… きっ
You can't even shake hands?
（紅莉栖）握手もできないの？
Japanese men don't know how to do anything.
日本の男の人って
常識が足りてないんじゃない？
（岡部）ぬうう
あっ あっ あああっ…
You're freaking out too much.
（紅莉栖）ビビりすぎ
（岡部）
あっ… 身にまとう殺気が
ハンパないからな
It's because I can feel murderous intent seeping from your every pore.
Could this be what they call the "martial arts"?
これが俗に言う
マーシャルアーツか？
（紅莉栖）ハア…
おっ どこへ行く？
Where are you going?
Honestly, I came here to see if your claim that I'd been stabbed was real,
（紅莉栖）本当は―
私が刺されたのを見たというのが
事実なのか
or just an excuse for sexual harassment.
セクハラ行為の言い訳なのか
But it seems something more important has come up.
その確認をしたくて
来たんですけど
This.
それよりも…
～
Parallel World
Paranoia
（阿万音鈴羽(あまねすずは)）ハア…
There's no damage to the stalk.
結合部に損傷はない
トリックではないようね
It's not some kind of trick.
She may attempt to trigger some sort of explosive.
爆発物を仕掛ける可能性がある
監視の目を緩めるな
Don't let her out of your sight for a second.
No, she won't.
（橋田）ないっちゅうの
（紅莉栖）ピンセットない？
Got any tweezers?
（岡部）ない
（紅莉栖）そう
No!
I see.
（岡部）なっ…
（紅莉栖）中はグズグズね
It's mushy inside.
（岡部）ううっ うあ！
（紅莉栖）味は…
It tastes...
ああ… ない　まっずい
Nothing.
Ew!
You zombie!
このゾンビめ
腹が減っているなら そう言え！
If you're hungry, say so.
I'll give you a banana.
バナナぐらい恵んでやる
I'm fine.
要りません
Who'd eat a pervert's banana, anyways?
誰が変態のバナナなんて
食べるもんですか
Wha—
なっ… 変態だと！
Pervert?
You poked at me, attempting to touch me out of nowhere.
いきなり人のこと つついて
体まで触ろうとして
Miss Makise? Miss Makise?
（橋田）牧瀬氏 牧瀬氏
（紅莉栖）はい？
Yes?
Could you say, "Who'd eat a pervert's banana, anyways?" once more?
“変態のバナナなんて
食べるもんですか”って―
もう一度 お願いできる？
できたら悔しそうな顔で
If possible, with an upset expression.
Upset?
（紅莉栖）悔しそうな？
（橋田）うん
Yes.
（紅莉栖）ううっ…
（岡部）フフッ
Why are you blushing?
何を赤くなっている？
Did you imagine something?
もしかして 何か想像したのか？
Out with it, girl genius.
言ってみろ天才少女
Shall we listen to what the genius imagined?
天才が何を想像したのか
ご高説願おうではないか
（紅莉栖）ううっ
It seems you're both perverts.
どうやら あなたたち２人とも
変態みたいね
（橋田）いやあ
（紅莉栖）褒めてない
Oh, my...
It's not a compliment.
I would say the person with the perverted imagination is the pervert.
（岡部）
むしろ変態な想像をしたほうが
変態だろう？
You perverted girl genius!
変態天才少女よ
Who's the pervert?
誰が変態よ！
オーケー
Okay...
To be honest, we're at the point where I could sue you for sexual harasssment,
正直 セクハラで すぐに
訴えてもいいレベルだけど―
but I'll ignore it for now.
今は不問にしておくわ
“今は”？
For now?
だから 詳しく教えて
So, tell me the details.
This banana has something to do with that microwave, right?
このバナナ
そのレンジと関係があるのよね？
（岡部）トップシークレットだ
It's top secret!
Future Gadget #8, the Phone Microwave (name subject to change),
未来ガジェット８号機
「電話レンジ（仮）(かっこかり)」は―
is my lab's secret weapon.
我が研究所の秘密兵器だからな
（紅莉栖）ん？
（橋田）でも牧瀬氏なら―
But Miss Makise might be able to explain how this strange device works.
このヘンテコな機能について
解明してくれるかもよ
（岡部）うん　いや しかし…
But...
You need to understand, we'll never figure this out on our own.
（橋田）つうか 僕らだけじゃ
絶対解明できないと思われ
（岡部）えっ んん
だが あくまで これは―
But this is the Future Gadget Lab's...
未来ガジェット研究所の…
おおっ！
フフフフッ
フハハハハハッ
You!
貴様！
クリスティーナとか言ったな
Christina, you said?
No, I never said that.
（紅莉栖）ひと言も言っとらんわ
I'll tell you the secrets of the Phone Microwave (name subject to change), on two conditions!
この「電話レンジ（仮）」の
秘密を知るには 条件がある
（紅莉栖）うっ…
（岡部）１つ
One, you must become a member of the Future Gadget Lab.
貴様には
この未来ガジェット研究所の―
ラボメンになってもらう
You want me to join your lab?
研究所のメンバーに
迎えてくれるってこと？
ん… でも 私 ８月中に
アメリカに帰る予定だけど
But I'm returning to America in August...
It can be just until then.
それまでで かまわん
And one more condition.
（岡部）それと もう１つ
（紅莉栖）まだあるの？
There's more?
Forget about any acts of sexual harassment I've committed.
（岡部）
俺が貴様に行ったセクハラ行為を
すべて不問にしろ
That's it.
以上だ
Okarin, you're a small person.
オカリン ちっちぇー
人としての器が
ちっちぇーっす
A very small person.
And I love that. Love it!
そこにシビれる 憧れる～
（岡部）だっ… うるさい！
Shut up!
Well?
どうだ？
悪くない条件だと思うがな
I think the conditions are very favorable...
Favorable to you.
（紅莉栖）
あんたにとってでしょ？
まったく…
Jeez...
ノルアドレナリンが
過剰分泌するわね
You're making my brain send out too much norepinephrine.
さあ どうする？
クリスティーナ
What will you do, Christina?
There's no "-tina"!
だから “ティーナ”って
付けるな
悪かったな ザ･ゾンビよ
Sorry, "The Zombie."
Say it right, Hououin Pervert-Kyouma!
ちゃんと呼べ！
鳳凰院(ほうおういん)変態凶真(きょうま)
黙れ！ 天才変態少女
くううっ…
Shut up!
Pervert Girl Genius!
（紅莉栖）ううっ…
Perverts glaring at one another... Win!
（橋田）
変態どうしの視殺戦　燃える！
Shut up, pervert!
（岡部･紅莉栖）黙れ！ 変態
Oh, fine.
しかたないわね
分かったわ
All right.
I accept.
条件をのむ
だから もう“変態”禁止
So, no more "Pervert."
I'll stop calling you one, too.
私も変態扱いしないから
Very well.
いいだろう
では たった今から貴様は
ラボメンナンバー００４
Then, from now on, you're Lab Member 004!
Christina!
クリスティーナだ！
No "-tina"!
（紅莉栖）“ティーナ”も禁止
Juicy Kara-age Number One... Wow!
（椎名(しいな)まゆり）
「ジューシーからあげNo.１(ワン)」
ワン！
I'm back!
Do you think it's a teleporter?
（まゆり）ただいま
（紅莉栖）本当にテレポートなの？
It's dangerous to jump to conclusions.
結論ありきで考えるのは危険よ
Then, what do you think it is?
（岡部）ならば 何だというんだ？
（紅莉栖）ん… 少なくとも―
At the very least,
it didn't teleport the single banana
バナナの房や
冷凍から揚げのときは―
One, two, three, four...
テレポートしなかったんでしょ？
or the banana bunch.
（まゆり）あれっ お客さん？
A guest?
あっ… フッ
Hello there.
お邪魔してます
牧瀬紅莉栖です
I'm Makise Kurisu.
I'm sorry for just showing up out of the blue.
いきなり押しかけてきて
ごめんなさい
I'm Shiina Mayuri.
椎名まゆりです
It seems I'm a lab member now as well.
なんか 私も
ラボメンになったみたいで
A lab member?
（まゆり）ラボメン？
（紅莉栖）ええ
Yes...
A female lab member!
女の子のラボメンだあ！
（紅莉栖）
そ… そんなに珍しいの？
Is it that rare?
うん うん うん！
Yes! Yes! Yes!
You're the first female lab member since Mayushii!
まゆしぃ以外では
初めての女の子のラボメンです
そうなんだ
I see.
よろしくね！
Nice to meet you.
Yes, nice to meet you.
ええ よろしく
What?
（岡部）なんだと！
（紅莉栖）ん… 何？
What happened?
There was an electrical release.
（岡部）
放電現象が起きていたらしい
え？ なんで先に言わないのよ
Why didn't you tell me earlier?
Give me the details.
具体的な状況を教えて
（橋田）え？ うーんと…
Um... Well...
だから レンジから
稲妻みたいなのが出て…
Some kind of lightning shot out from the microwave.
When?
（岡部）いつの話だ？
Yesterday, around noon.
（橋田）昨日の昼だったかな
オカリンが―
You saw the alert about the satellite crash and ran out,
人工衛星が墜落したニュース見て
飛び出していって―
and I connected my phone to it.
自分の携帯
こいつにつないで…
あっ！
じゃあ
あのメールを送ったとき―
Then, when I sent that message,
your phone was hooked up to the Phone Microwave (name subject to change)?
お前の携帯は
「電話レンジ（仮）」に―
つながっていたんだな？
The one about Miss Makise being stabbed?
“牧瀬氏が刺された”
とかいうメール？
That was a week ago, wasn't it?
あれ１週間前じゃん？
（岡部）ん… 違う！
No, that was yesterday!
あれは昨日の昼に…
Where is it? Where is it?
どこだ？ どこだ？
なぜ ない！
Why isn't it here?!
When this happened, what was the microwave doing?
（紅莉栖）
放電が起きたときの
レンジの状態は？
I was running a systems test...
動作テストしてたから
逆回転機能 使用中だったかな？
so I think it was during the reverse spin testing.
再現してみたほうが
よさそうね
We should try to recreate the situation.
（岡部）まゆり！
Mayuri, bring me the Juicy Kara-age Number One!
「ジューシーからあげNo.１」を
ここへ！
Okay!
（まゆり）ううー
あっ みんなも食べる？
Want some, anyone?
１個ずつなら あげてもいいよ
I can give each of you one.
Do we need to put something in there?
（紅莉栖）入れる必要あるの？
I want to see,
（岡部）逆回転時
中に入っている物の反応を見たい
what happens to its contents when it rotates backwards.
Daru.
ダル
Assistant, send a message to my phone.
助手　俺の携帯にメールを
いつから あんたの助手になった？
Since when did I become your assistant?
And I don't know your address anyways.
つうか あんたのアドレスなんて
知らないし
使えない助手め
Useless assistant.
Daru, your phone's fine.
ダル
お前の携帯でいい
What should the content be?
文面は？
Let me see.
（岡部）そうだな
"Christina is a pervert."
クリスティーナは変態で…
“変態禁止”って言っただろ
I told you that's off-limits.
じゃあ あいだ取って
“オカリンは変態”っと
Then we'll split the difference and go with "Okarin is a pervert"...
Wha—
（岡部）なっ…
（紅莉栖）橋田さん グッジョブ！
Mr. Hashida, good job!
All right, sending.
（橋田）じゃあ 送信するお
Now, we wait for the message to reach the phone...
（岡部）あとは携帯にメールが…
I bet it's ready now!
（まゆり）
そろそろ いいんじゃないかな？
（岡部）なっ… 待て！
（橋田）え？
Wait!
（まゆり）ん？ うわっ
（岡部）んんっ！ うっ…
（まゆり）ゴホッ ゴホッ ゴホッ
（岡部）大丈夫か？ ゴホッ
（まゆり）うん　うっ…
Are you all right?
Yeah...
（橋田）うっ ゴホッ ゴホッ
Gotta turn on the fan!
換気 換気 ゴホッ
What was that?
（紅莉栖）どういうこと？
The EM waves, maybe?
（岡部）電磁波の力か？
Don't be stupid.
バカ言わないで！
電子レンジの電磁波が―
A microwave's EM waves couldn't split a desk just like that.
こんな短時間で
机 割るなんて ありえない
They're all black!
（まゆり）ああ！ 黒焦げだー
せっかく買ってきたのに…
And I just bought them, too!
What'll we do about the hole in the floor?
床の穴どうする？
ブラウン氏に見つかったら
シャレで済まないレベル
If Mr. Braun finds that, we'll be in serious trouble.
（岡部）うっ… ああ！
Well?
（紅莉栖）どう？
（岡部）あった
It's here.
Received Mail
Time:
Sender: Daru
Subject: (no subject)
Okarin is a pervert
7/24, 17:30.
“受信日時 ７月24日 17時半”
It really went back to the past...
間違いない 過去に…
（岡部）ハッ！
（紅莉栖）あ…
（岡部）
フフフッ ハッハッハッ
Did you find something?
何か分かったの？
ああ すべてがつながった
Yes. It's all coming together!
I can see it...
見えたぞ
The one answer this all points to!
一連の事件が意味する
唯一無二の答えが！
Really?
（紅莉栖）ホントに？
房から ちぎられたバナナは
房へと戻った
The banana, split off from the bunch, returned!
The message traveled five days into the past!
メールは５日前へと送られた
No way. You can't mean...
そんな… まさか
（岡部）その“まさか”だ！
That's right!
この「電話レンジ（仮）」は…
The Phone Microwave (name subject to change) is...
（紅莉栖）あっ…
（橋田）あ…
（まゆり）あー
（紅莉栖）ああ…
...a time machine!
（岡部）タイムマシンだ！
（鈴羽の鼻歌）
（岡部のいびき）
（岡部）うううっ うう…
ハア…
Thirteen messages?
メール… 13件？
“閃光(せんこう)の…”
The lightning...
Oh, right.
（岡部）ああ そうだった
I dubbed her the "Shining Finger."
シャイニング･フィンガーと
名付けたんだった
But this many?
しかし この量…
"Message me now."
“すぐメールして”
"Are you asleep?"
“もしかして寝てるの？”
"How long are you going to sleep?"
“いつまで寝てるつもり？”
Daru?
ダル… ふああー
Wanna go for a walk?
ハア… 散歩でも行くか
（橋田）ハア…
（岡部）どうした？
What's wrong?
（橋田）ダメージ デカいよ
徹夜で成果ゼロなんて
The damage is pretty bad.
I worked all night, with nothing to show for it.
I regret even trying.
やったこと後悔している
なんで ゲルバナに
ならなくなったんだ？
Why aren't they turning into gel-banas anymore?
（岡部）フウッ
Hell if I know.
知るか
That was the only time we were able to send a message.
メールを送れたのは
あれ１回きりだしな
Shouldn't we call Miss Makise back?
（橋田）
牧瀬氏 呼び戻したほうが
いいんじゃね？
You know that's not going to happen.
（岡部）
無理に決まっているだろうが
No way.
（紅莉栖）ウソ…
タイムマシンなんて！
A time machine?
うっ…
（岡部）…って
出ていったきりなんだからな
She never came back.
What's with that?
何だったんだろう
（岡部）ん？
何だ？ これは
What is this?
（橋田）ＬＨＣ
（岡部）はあ？
The LHC.
What?
The Large Hadron Collider,
（橋田）
ラージハドロンコライダー
ＳＥＲＮ(セルン)の素粒子加速器
SERN's particle accelerator.
癒やされるよねえ
Feels nice, just by looking at it...
SERN maintains an exclusive monopoly on time machines.
（ジョン･タイター）
“タイムマシンはＳＥＲＮによって
独占されています”
John Titor...
ジョン･タイター
Oh, the one you were talking about.
ああ
この前 言ってたやつ？
@channel can't get enough of the guy.
今「アットちゃんねる」で
祭りみたいだね
What is SERN?
（岡部）ＳＥＲＮとは何だ？
（橋田）ああっ
タイターは言っていた
Titor explained that they completed a time machine by 2034!
“ＳＥＲＮが2034年までに
タイムマシンを完成させる”と
I have no idea what you're talking—
イミフなんですけど
Just tell me!
（岡部）
いいから教えろ！
ＳＥＲＮとは？
What is SERN—
Calm down.
だから
欧州素粒子原子核研究機構の略称
It's the acronym for the European Organization for Nuclear Research and Particle Physics.
Its H.Q. is just outside Geneva.
本部はジュネーブ郊外
As the name suggests, its main work is in particle physics.
名前のとおり
メインは素粒子物理学の研究
そのための世界的な設備を
いくつも持っている
It also has some of the world's best facilities for it:
the Low Energy Antiproton Ring,
低速反陽子リング
the Proton Synchrotron Booster,
陽子シンクロトロンブースター
the Large Electron–Positron Collider...
大型電子陽電コライダー
and the last boss,
…で ラスボスは
世界一の素粒子加速器
the world's biggest particle accelerator,
the Large Hadron Collider~
ラージハドロンコライダーたん
There were rumors that the LHC could generate a miniature black hole.
ＬＨＣは使い方次第で―
ミニブラックホールが
できるかもって―
うわさもあったけどね
A black hole...
（岡部）ブラックホール
Daru.
（岡部）ダル
（橋田）何ぞ？
'Sup?
Didn't one proposed time travel method utilize a miniature black hole?
たしか タイムトラベルを
実現させる方法の１つに―
ミニブラックホールを使ったものが
あったよな？
Yeah, it did.
ああ
あるけど…
But you attended Miss Makise's lecture, didn't you?
この前 牧瀬氏が
講義で言ったっしょ？
She said creating a black hole was impossible.
そもそも
ブラックホールの生成が無理だって
だがＬＨＣがある以上
作られる可能性だって…
But if the LHC exists, then it's possible—
あるあ！
いや ねえよ
It is!
...not possible.
SERN's publicly denied it.
ＳＥＲＮが公式に否定してる
しかし 火のない所に
煙は立たないとも言う
But they say, "where there's smoke, there's fire."
俺だ
It's me.
No Cell Phones
フッ そうだ
分かっている
That's right. I know.
エル･プサイ･コングルゥ
El Psy Congroo.
Who, exactly, are you fighting?
おまいは誰と戦ってるんだ？
There's only one thing for us to do now.
（岡部）こうなった以上
俺たちのやるべきことは１つ
Go to Feyris's!
フェイリスたんの所に行くこと？
違う！
お前はスーパーハカーだろ？
No!
You're a super haker, right?
You should smile smugly!
すべてをくんで
ニヤリと笑え！
It's "hacker," not "haker," all right?
“ハカー”じゃなくて
“ハッカー”な
You understand the rest?
（岡部）あとは分かるな？
Not a bit.
いいえ 全然
Hack into SERN.
ＳＥＲＮをハッキングしろ
That's it.
以上だ
Okarin... You're joking, right?
オカリン ギャグだよな？
You need to find out what evil they're up to
（岡部）やつらの悪事を暴き―
and find hints about the time machine.
タイムマシンについてのヒントを
手に入れろ
Whether we make the Phone Microwave (name subject to change) into a real time machine
「電話レンジ（仮）」を―
タイムマシンとして
使えるようにするか
or let it rest forever in the lab storeroom is up to your skills.
このまま ラボの倉庫で
眠らせることになるか
お前の腕にかかっている
Don't blame me for whatever happens!
どうなっても知らないよ
Two orders of beef bowl.
（店員）牛丼２人前
（橋田）え？
800 yen total.
（店員）合わせて800円
（橋田）オカリーン！
Okarin!
（鈴羽の鼻歌）
Slacking off again?
（岡部）またサボりか？
（鈴羽）あっ　ああ うん
Yeah, the shop's boring.
だって お店 退屈なんだもん
することなくて
Nothing to do.
You're more of a bicycle shop now.
（岡部）それでは
まるで自転車屋だな
Hey, what are you guys doing on the second floor?
ねえねえ それより君たちって
２階で何してるの？
Future Gadget Lab, right?
未来ガジェット研究所
っていうんでしょ？
（岡部）なぜ その名前を？
Where did you learn that name?
（鈴羽）あ…
（岡部）ハッ！ うっ…
Future Gadget Lab
If you know that much, then fine.
そこまで知られたからには
しかたあるまい
We're fighting against an organization that rules the world from the shadows.
我々は世界を陰から操る
闇の機関と戦っているのだ
Just now, we're hacking into that organization.
今もちょうど 機関にハッキングを
仕掛けているところでな
ああ！ じゃあ もしかして
ＳＥＲＮっていうのは―
So, is SERN that organization?
その闇の機関のこと？
（岡部）なぜ それを？
（鈴羽）ごめん
How did you know?
I'm sorry.
Actually, I overheard you guys.
実は話し声
聞こえてきちゃってさ
I said I was bored, didn't I?
ほら 退屈って言ったでしょ？
だから つい…
So, I accidentally...
（岡部）盗み聞きしたというのか？
You were spying on us?
I could hear you...
聞こえてくるんだもん
But don't worry.
でも安心して！
これでも 口は堅いから
I'm good at keeping my mouth shut.
（岡部）あっ…
フウ… またか
Again?
What? A message that someone died?
（鈴羽）何？
死亡通知でも来た？
Someone died?
“死亡通知”？
あっ いや…
冗談 冗談
N-No... I was just kidding.
This girl's obsessed with some old PC called an IBN 5100.
ＩＢＮ5100とかいう
レトロパソコンに―
やたら執着している女がいてな
An IBN?
（鈴羽）“ＩＢＮ”？
（岡部）知っているのか？
You know it?
あっ あ… うん
Um... Yeah.
それも聞いていたのか？
You heard it, too?
（鈴羽）違う 違う！
それはネットで見たんだ
No, I saw it on the Internet.
You know, that guy who claimed to be a time traveler?
ほら タイムトラベラーとかいう人
ジョン･タイターだっけ？
John Titor, was it?
“タイター”？
Titor?
なんか「アットちゃんねる」に
書いてたよ
It was on @channel.
The IBN 5100 was built before the widespread use of the BASIC language,
ＩＢＮ5100は―
ベーシック言語が出来る以前に
作られたパソコンだから―
ＩＢＮ独自のプログラム言語も
読めるとかなんとか…
so it can read IBN's proprietary programming language or something...
Really?
（岡部）本当か？
（鈴羽）う… うん
Y-Yeah.
ハッ そういえば
2000年に現れたタイターも…
Come to think of it, the Titor who appeared in 2000 also...
（岡部の荒い息）
You all seem to have fixed ideas about the nature of time.
（タイター）“皆さんは
時間の概念について”
032 Name: Chestnut Rice and Kamehameha [sage]
This is getting more disappointing
None of this is really concrete
I realize you're doing your best to sound realistic,
but you can't fool me.
“固定観念に
支配されているようです”
Time isn't a single line, moving from past to future.
“時間は過去から未来へ
たった一つの川が―”
“流れているようなものでは
ありません”
Let's say I were to go back in time and kill someone we'll call "A."
“例えば 私が過去へ戻って
Ａという人物を殺したとします”
This alters something called the divergence number,
“するとダイバージェンスと
呼ばれる数値に変動が起こり―”
and the world line moves to a world without this person named A.
“世界線は
Ａという人物のいない世界へ―”
“移動するのです”
When there's a world line shift, people's memories are altered.
“世界線移動のとき
人々の記憶は再構築されます”
In other words, memories of the world line where A existed are deleted,
“つまり―”
“Ａという人物がいた以前の
世界線の記憶は消去され―”
and replaced with memories of a world line where A doesn't exist.
“新たに出来た Ａという人物が
いない世界線の記憶が―”
“再構築されるのです”
I'm more interested in how SERN, a research organization, ends up as the planetary ruler.
（栗悟飯(くりごはん)とカメハメ波(は)）“それより
研究機関だったＳＥＲＮが”
214 Name: Chestnut Rice and Kamehameha [sage]
I'm more interested in how SERN,
a research organization, ends up as the planetary ruler.
It's a question I've been wondering for a while now.
“いつの間にか
世界を支配する統治機構に―”
“変貌した件について
前から質問しているわけだが”
It's a question I've been wondering for a while now.
Don't believe what SERN says.
（タイター）
“ＳＥＲＮの言うことを
安易に信じてはいけません”
343 Name: Anonymous [sage]
And this results in a dystopia?
They've already succeeded in creating a miniature black hole.
357 Name: Anonymous [sage]
What's a dystopia?
“すでに彼らは マイクロ
ブラックホール生成に―”
“成功しています”
“ディストピアとは
共産主義が復活し―”
It would be easiest to describe a dystopia as the revival of communism,
and the world's reversion to the 18th century's living standards.
“生活レベルが
18世紀に戻ったと言えば―”
“分かりやすいでしょうか”
By 2036, SERN holds most of the world's science and technology.
“2036年では―”
“科学技術のほとんどを
ＳＥＲＮが握っているのです”
And you need the IBN 5100 to change this future?
（岡部）
“その未来を変えるために
ＩＢＮ5100が必要だというのか？”
That's correct.
（タイター）“そうなります”
I need the IBN 5100's abilities to stop their plans.
“ＳＥＲＮの企(たくら)みを防ぐには
ＩＢＮ5100の機能が必要なのです”
（岡部）“2000年に現れた
ジョン･タイターも”
The John Titor who appeared in 2000 said the same thing.
“確か そんなことを言っていた”
The "me" who appeared ten years ago?
（タイター）
“10年前に現れた私ですか”
As I've said, I've unfortunately never been to the year 2000.
“前にも言ったように―”
“残念ながら
私は2000年には行っていません”
But, it's possible you saw me in a different world line.
“…が あなたは―”
“ほかの世界線の私を
見た可能性があります”
Interesting.
“面白いです”
I'd like to talk to you in detail.
“あなたとは 一度ゆっくり
お話ししてみたい”
This is my mail address.
*In 2015, WW3 occurs.
*In 2036, Earth is polluted
by nuclear warfare.
*I've travelled from 2036
to acquire an IBN 5100.
*The IBN 5100 has a
hidden function.
*Only a few IBN engineers
know of it.
“私のメールアドレスです”
If you contact me, I'll answer.
“連絡いただければ
お返事します”
フフンッ
（橋田）もうすぐなんだよ
I've almost got it.
If I can just access the SQL table list,
ＳＱＬのテーブル一覧さえ
手に入れば―
パスワードの特定 余裕なんだよ
figuring out the password should be easy.
Good morning!
（まゆり）おはよー
（岡部）おっ まゆりか
Mayuri?
こんな早くから どうした？
What brings you here so early?
（まゆり）
２日連続 徹夜って聞いたから
差し入れ買ってきたよ
I heard you've been up two nights in a row, so I brought snacks.
フフッ じゃーん
Here you go.
（岡部）おおっ！ おでん缶か
Canned fishcake stew!
Great!
ありがたい
また頼むぞ まゆり
Bring me another sometime, Mayuri.
Mayushii doesn't have enough pocket money to treat you too often.
しょっちゅう おごれるほど―
まゆしぃのポケットマネーは
多くないのです
I need to buy my Rai-Net sausage, as well!
「雷(らい)ネットソーセージ」も
買わなきゃいけないし
（岡部）
アハッ　また うーぱか？
Upa again?
（まゆり）
なので 大事に味わって
食べてほしいのです
So I want you to enjoy this!
（岡部）うん
There's some for Daru and Kurisu, too.
ダル君と紅莉栖ちゃんの分も
あるからね
（橋田）うーん もう！
だから ここじゃなくて…
That's not it!
He's not listening at all.
（まゆり）全然 聞こえてないね
I told him to take a break, though.
（岡部）
少し休めと言ってるんだがな
（まゆり）
スーパーハカー魂がメラメラ
バーニングしちゃってるね
His super haker's soul is burning bright!
（橋田）くっ…
“ハカー”って言うな！
Don't say "haker"!
（岡部）あたっ…
But it's not good to nose around in the secrets of others, isn't it?
（まゆり）でも のぞき見は
悪いことなんだよね？
（岡部）
ＳＥＲＮの陰謀を暴くためだ
This is to reveal SERN's plots.
（まゆり）
それでも 紅莉栖ちゃんも
きっと怒ってたから―
Even so...
I'm sure Kurisu left because she was mad.
飛び出していっちゃったんじゃ
ないかな？
いや…
あれはハッキングとは関係なく―
No, that had nothing to do with the hacking.
My assistant ran off on her own.
助手が勝手にだな
I wonder if she'll come back...
また来てくれるかな？
紅莉栖ちゃん
（まゆり）はむっ
（岡部）ん…
（まゆり）あれっ 何？
Huh?
What?
I'll trade you a mandarin for a beef strip.
（岡部）さつまと牛スジを交換だ
（まゆり）ええ？
それなら ウズラがいいな
I'd rather have a quail egg, then.
（岡部）ダメだ
No.
I like quail eggs almost as much as I like beef strips.
俺は牛スジの次に
ウズラが好きなのだ
まゆしぃも
ウズラ好きだもん
Mayushii likes quail eggs, too!
Then I'll give you a fish sausage instead.
なら ちくわで
手を打ってくれ
うーん…
さつまよりは ちくわかな
I guess I like fish sausages more than mandarins.
Okay, then negotiations have concluded.
（岡部）よし 交渉成立だ
Then here's my beef strip...
じゃあ まゆしぃの牛スジ…
あれ？
Huh?
I ate it already.
（岡部）もう 頂いた
（まゆり）ええっ いつの間に…
When did you...
（岡部）あむっ
（まゆり）ハア…
It was good.
（岡部）なかなか うまかったぞ
フフッ
I got it!
（橋田）キターッ！
I got it! I got it! I got it! I got it! I got it!
キタ キタ キタ キタ キター！
オラー！
Now give up, and show me everything.
観念して 俺の前に
全部さらしやがれっての！
I got it!
（橋田）キタ！ ＩＤゲット！
（岡部）やったのか？
ID get!
You did it?
Mission complete!
ミッション コンプリート！
（まゆり）
わあ！ ハハッ すごいね
よく分かんないけど
I don't understand, but wow.
Well, the hacking's complete,
まあ ハッキングしたっつっても
管理者のＩＤじゃなければ―
but there are limits to what I can see without being an admin.
見られる範囲は限られるっつうか
おっぱいしか見えない的な？
It's like I can only see the boobs.
You're so naughty, Daru.
ダル君 エッチだね
What did you get?
内容は？
So far, just some e-mails.
（橋田）まだメールが
いくつか出てきただけ
（岡部）英語か！
English?
Let's get Dr. Excite in here.
「エキサイト」先生にご登場願え
No way, that's a pain.
（橋田）…んなめんどいこと
してられないっつうの
意訳すると…
ハーイ ポール
It says, "Hi, Paul!"
We don't need your acting.
（岡部）そういう演技は無用だ
さいですか　ええと…
No?
Let's see...
"The LHC is working well."
“ＬＨＣの調子は良好だ”
“こいつは あくまで
猫みたいに気まぐれだが―”
"It's as fickle as a cat, but for the past month,"
“ここ１カ月は
驚くほど調子がいい”
"...it's been working surprisingly well."
What's he talking about?
（岡部）何のことだ？
（橋田）さあ？
Don't know.
それより…
Anyways, does anything here mention a time machine?
タイムマシンの痕跡のような文章は
ないのか？
The phrase "time machine" doesn't show up,
（橋田）
“タイムマシン”って単語は
ないけど―
but in the last month, the phrase "Z-program" has been used over a hundred times.
“Ｚプログラム”って単語が―
ここ１カ月で
100回以上 使われてる
Let's see...
えっと…
"Z-Program Experiment Report 137."
“第137次 Ｚプログラム
実験レポート”
"The miniature black hole mission has already been established,"
“ミニブラックホール
生成ミッションは―”
“すでに確立しているため
報告は省く”
"...so I'll skip that report."
Miniature black hole...
（岡部）“ミニブラックホール”
Seems like it.
（橋田）…みたいだね
They announced publically that those experiments were a failure.
公式には
実験は成功していないって―
発表されてるのにな
（岡部）その先は？
What else does it say?
"Experiment result..."
“実験結果”
"Human is dead,"
“ヒューマン イズ デッド
ミスマッチ”
"...mismatch."
Human is dead?
（岡部）
“ヒューマン イズ デッド”？
（橋田）うん
（岡部）人が…
Someone...
...died.
死んだ？
～